Guide to the Peter Newell Family Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Compiled over a forty-year period by Baker, with the help of his mother and step-father, the Research Files contain correspondence with and clippings on nearly everyone who had any personal or professional relationship with Peter Newell. Baker also researched the areas of the country where the artist, his ancestors and his relatives lived or traveled, and gathered primary and secondary source material on those places and their inhabitants. Following clues found in Newell's correspondence and personal papers, Baker tracked down people (or their descendants) associated with the artist, then wrote introductory letters followed up with tailored, situation-specific questionnaires that served as an interview covering every aspect of their knowledge of Newell, his habits and the society in which he lived. Baker's files contain clippings and obituaries on these correspondents as well, and hold a wealth of information that provides a context for Peter Newell's life and activities.
The files have been arranged either by the subject's relationship to Newell or by the area of the country where Newell made their acquaintance, beginning with a set of files on the authors and publishers associated with Newell's illustrations, one on Newell's corporate clients, and one on his family members. Next follow files on the locales important in Newell's life, and their residents and institutions, arranged by state and then by town or city within. The most extensive and comprehensive files concern the New Jersey town of Leonia; it is here that Baker's investigative work is probably the most valuable, for he collected not only information on the people who made up that community, but also their personal descriptions, recollections and feelings about life there in the period 1890-1920.
Baker's research files conclude with miscellaneous research material, containing biographical material on other artists, opinions of Newell solicited from his contemporaries, and correspondence with other institutions and collectors holding Peter Newell books and drawings.
Series VIII ends with Baker's Personal Correspondence and Papers (non-Peter Newell related) which includes material regarding the settlement of estate of his father, Alfred Z. Baker Sr.
Series IX. Work by Other Artists, (Boxes 225-233), holds drawings, paintings, prints and sculpture by Newell's friends and contemporaries. Some of the work was created for periodicals, and the collection is particularly strong on illustrations published in Harper's magazines in the year 1898. A few of these illustrations can be seen hanging on the walls in photographs of Newell's home studio. Other works were gifts made to the Baker children by Leonia artists.
Series X. William Henry Jackson Photographs, (Boxes 234-239), contains a selection of sixty-six mounted mammoth-plate prints of the American West and Mexico by Jackson. Provenance is undocumented but it is thought that the photographs might have been acquired by Peter Newell while he was living in Colorado in 1888.
Advertising -- Pictorial works; African American wit and humor; Artist colonies -- New Jersey -- Leonia; Children -- Books and reading; Children's literature -- United States; Comic books, strips, etc.; Toy and movable books; Illustration of books -- United States; Illustrators -- Illinois -- Archives; Illustrators -- New Jersey -- Archives; Magazine illustration -- United States; Photography -- Colorado -- 19th century; Photography -- Illinois -- 19th century; Toy and movable books -- Specimens; Illinois -- Description and travel; Kansas -- Description and travel; New Jersey -- Description and travel; Calendars (documents by form) -- United States; Drawings (visual works) -- United States; Lantern slides -- United States; Mechanical toys -- United States; Oil paintings (visual works) -- United States; Photographs -- United States; Preparatory drawings -- United States; Sketchbooks -- United States; Tintypes (prints) -- United States; Watercolors (paintings) -- United States; Illustrators -- Illinois; Illustrators -- New Jersey; Baker, A. Z. (Alfred Zantzinger), 1870-1940; Bradley, Frances Sage, 1862-1949; McCormick, Howard, 1875-1943; Newell, Clendenon Sheaf, 1892-1918; Newell, Peter, 1862-1924; Art Students League (New York, N.Y.); Cornell University -- Students; Harper & Brothers; Periodical Publishers Association of America; Exposition universelle ( 1900 Paris, France); World's Columbian Exposition ( 1893 Chicago, Ill.)
- Peter and Leona Newell Papers, 1840-1985; Series I; 11.8; (20 boxes)
  Scope and Contents
  The series is arranged in five subseries: Correspondence (subdivided by Immediate Family, Other Family and Friends, and Professional Correspondence); Personal Papers; Creative Writings; Commissioned Works; and Publicity and Writings.
  - CORRESPONDENCE
    - Immediate Family Correspondence
      The family section consists of correspondence between Peter Newell, his wife, and their three children. For reasons of volume and integrity, correspondence between Clendenon Newell and his parents is filed separately following the correspondence among Peter and Leona Newell and their daughters; within the subdivisions all files are arranged chronologically. Correspondence prior to 1924 consists principally of letters between Peter Newell and his children and Peter Newell to his wife. Letters written among the children are filed in a separate series for Clendenon Newell (Series IV) and Helen Newell Baker Gordon (Series V).
      - Newell, Peter and Leona, and their daughters
        Files titled "Letters..." contain only letters from Peter Newell.
        - Correspondence, 1884-94 (Box 1, Folder 1)
        - Correspondence, 1896 (Box 1, Folder 2)
        - Letters from Europe, 1897 (Box 1, Folder 3)
        - Correspondence, 1898 (Box 1, Folder 4)
        - Letters from Gloucester, MA, 1899 Aug (Box 1, Folder 5)
        - Letters from Paris, France, 1900 Apr (Box 1, Folder 6)
        - Letters from Paris, France, 1900 May (Box 1, Folder 7)
        - Letters from Paris, France, 1900 Jun (Box 1, Folder 8)
        - Letters from Paris, France, 1900 Jul (Box 1, Folder 9)
        - Correspondence, 1901-02 (Box 1, Folder 10)
        - Correspondence, 1903-06 (Box 1, Folder 11)
        - Correspondence, 1907 (Box 1, Folder 12)
        - Letters from Charleston, SC, 1910 Jun-Jul (Box 1, Folder 13)
        - Letters from Maine and Illinois, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 14)
        - Letters from political conventions, 1912 (Box 1, Folder 15)
        - Correspondence, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 16)
        - Letters from Charleston, SC, 1914 Feb (Box 1, Folder 17)
        - Letters from Charleston, SC, 1914 Mar 1-15 (Box 1, Folder 18)
        - Letters from Charleston, SC, 1914 Mar 16-31 (Box 1, Folder 19)
        - Letters from Charleston, SC, 1914 Apr (Box 1, Folder 20)
        - Correspondence, 1916 Mar (Box 2, Folder 21)
        - Correspondence, 1919-20 (Box 2, Folder 22)
        - Correspondence, 1923-24 (Box 2, Folder 23)
        - Correspondence, 1928, 1930 (Box 2, Folder 24)
        - Correspondence, 1931-33 (Box 2, Folder 25)
        - Correspondence, 1934 (Box 2, Folder 26)
        - Correspondence, 1935-36 (Box 2, Folder 27)
        - Undated correspondence (Box 2, Folder 28)
      - Newell, Clendenon Sheaf
        - Correspondence, 1899-1902, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 29)
        - Correspondence, 1907-10 (Box 2, Folder 30)
        - Correspondence, 1911 (Box 2, Folder 31)
        - Correspondence, 1912 Jun, Aug (Box 2, Folder 32)
        - Correspondence, 1912 Sep (Box 2, Folder 33)
        - Correspondence, 1912 Oct 4-19 (Box 2, Folder 34)
        - Correspondence, 1912 Oct 20-31 (Box 2, Folder 35)
        - Correspondence, 1912 Nov 2-16 (Box 2, Folder 36)
        - Correspondence, 1912 Nov 18-30 (Box 2, Folder 37)
        - Correspondence, 1912 Dec (Box 2, Folder 38)
        - Correspondence, 1913 Jan 6-19 (Box 3, Folder 39)
        - Outgoing, 1913 Jan 20-30 (Box 3, Folder 40)
        - Outgoing, 1913 Feb (Box 3, Folder 41)
        - Outgoing, 1913 Mar (Box 3, Folder 42)
        - Outgoing, 1913 Apr (Box 3, Folder 43)
        - Correspondence, 1913 May-Jul (Box 3, Folder 44)
        - Outgoing, 1913 Sep (Box 3, Folder 45)
        - Correspondence, 1913 Oct (Box 3, Folder 46)
        - Correspondence, 1913 Nov (Box 3, Folder 47)
        - Correspondence, 1913 Dec (Box 3, Folder 48)
        - Outgoing, 1914 Jan (Box 4, Folder 49)
        - Correspondence, 1914 Feb 1-15 (Box 4, Folder 50)
        - Correspondence, 1914 Feb 16-30 (Box 4, Folder 51)
        - Correspondence, 1914 Mar (Box 4, Folder 52)
        - Correspondence, 1914 Apr (Box 4, Folder 53)
        - Correspondence, 1914 May (Box 4, Folder 54)
        - Correspondence, 1914 Jun, Aug (Box 4, Folder 55)
        - Outgoing, 1914 Sep (Box 4, Folder 56)
        - Correspondence, 1914 Oct 1-9 (Box 4, Folder 57)
        - Correspondence, 1914 Oct 10-28 (Box 4, Folder 58)
        - Outgoing, 1914 Nov (Box 4, Folder 59)
        - Outgoing, 1914 Dec (Box 4, Folder 60)
        - Correspondence, 1915 Jan (Box 5, Folder 61)
        - Correspondence, 1915 Feb (Box 5, Folder 62)
        - Correspondence, 1915 Mar (Box 5, Folder 63)
        - Correspondence, 1915 Apr (Box 5, Folder 64)
        - Correspondence, 1915 May (Box 5, Folder 65)
        - Outgoing, 1915 Jun (Box 5, Folder 66)
        - Undated correspondence, re: college life, [1912-15] (Box 5, Folder 67)
        - Correspondence, 1916 Mar, May (Box 5, Folder 68)
        - Correspondence, 1917 May (Box 5, Folder 69)
        - Outgoing, 1917 Jun 2-15 (Box 5, Folder 70)
        - Correspondence, 1917 Jun 16-27 (Box 5, Folder 71)
        - Outgoing, 1917 Jul 1-15 (Box 5, Folder 72)
        - Correspondence, 1917 Jul 16-30 (Box 5, Folder 73)
        - Outgoing, 1917 Aug (Box 5, Folder 74)
        - Outgoing, 1918 Apr-May (Box 6, Folder 75)
        - Outgoing, 1918 Jun-Aug (Box 6, Folder 76)
        - Correspondence, 1918 Sep-Nov (Box 6, Folder 77)
        - Typed transcriptions of letters from September 1918, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 78)
        - Undated correspondence, re: military life, [1916-18] (Box 6, Folder 79)
        - Empty envelopes, 1918 (Box 6, Folder 80)
        - Empty envelopes and newspaper clippings (returned by military), 1918 (Box 6, Folder 81)
    - Other Family and Friends Correspondence
      - Ashcraft, Albert Ashcraft, Helen
        - Outgoing, 1881-82 (Box 6, Folder 82)
        - Outgoing, 1883-84 (Box 6, Folder 83)
        - Outgoing, 1885 (Box 6, Folder 84)
      - Ashcraft, Alva, 1879 Jul (Box 6, Folder 85)
      - Baker, Alfred Z., Sr., 1901, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 86)
      - Baker, Alfred (Tony) Z., Jr., 1911-21, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 87)
      - Bradley, Frances Sage, 1915-20 (Box 6, Folder 88)
      - Bradley, Florence Bradley, Horace, 1895-96 (Box 6, Folder 89)
      - Breck, George, 1898-1920 (Box 6, Folder 90)
      - Brown, John N., 1922 (Box 6, Folder 91)
      - Clendenon, Louis K., Mrs., 1912 Mar 12 (Box 6, Folder 92)
      - Cosgrove, Betty (Helen) Baker, 1936, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 93)
      - Covey, Arthur, 1928 Jun 20 (Box 6, Folder 94)
      - Gordon, Kate A., 1923 Apr 19 (Box 6, Folder 95)
      - Gordon, Marcus Acheson, 1917-24 (Box 6, Folder 96)
      - Gordon, Robert (Stubby) Bruce, 1914-28 (Box 6, Folder 97)
      - Hixson, Linda Carver, 1919-27 (Box 7, Folder 98)
      - Hooper, Ella Ashcraft, 1879-1908 (Box 7, Folder 99)
      - Hooper, Richard
        - Outgoing, 1879-80 (Box 7, Folder 100)
        - Outgoing, 1881-83 (Box 7, Folder 101)
        - Outgoing, 1884-86 (Box 7, Folder 102)
      - John, Alice, 1944 (Box 7, Folder 103)
      - Jones, Edmund Hazen Jones, Sara, 1912-49 (Box 7, Folder 104)
      - Lydecker, Sally McCormick, 1948, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 105)
      - McCormick children, 1922, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 106)
      - McCormick, Frederick, 1911-12 (Box 7, Folder 107)
      - McCormick, Howard, 1911-14, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 108)
      - McCormick, Peter Newell, 1948 (Box 7, Folder 109)
      - Morriss, Dudley Morris, Fannie, 1945-48, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 110)
      - Nankivel, Amanda Newell, 1898 Jul 30 (Box 7, Folder 111)
      - Nankivel, Claude M. autograph album and correspondence, 1889-1917, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 112)
      - Newell, Charles Henry, 1885 Dec 7 (Box 7, Folder 113)
      - Newell, George F. and Louisa D., letter from Peter Newell with drawing of his residence in New York, 1885 Oct 18 (Box 7, Folder 114)
      - Nichols, Samuel W., Mrs., 1884-85 (Box 7, Folder 115)
      - Reynolds, Marion (May) Ashcraft, 1883, 1944 (Box 7, Folder 116)
      - Roosevelt, Kermit, 1901-02 (Box 7, Folder 117)
      - Smith, Bera Smith, Edna Ashcraft, 1899-1904, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 118)
      - Worthen, Louella Newell Smith, Lucille Worthen, 1914-49 (Box 7, Folder 119)
      - Wyckoff, James T., ca. 1923 (Box 7, Folder 120)
      - Christmas and New Year cards, 1912-22, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 121)
      - Miscellaneous correspondents, 1879-1954, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 122)
      - Envelopes, empty (letters missing)
        - Addressed to Leona Ashcraft, 1878-85 (Box 7, Folder 123)
        - Addressed to Leona and Peter Newell, 1885-1933 (Box 7, Folder 124)
    - Professional Correspondence
      Contains correspondence and ephemera related to Peter Newell's business matters, colleagues, and professional associations in which he was involved.
      - Authors' League of America, 1913, 1917 (Box 8, Folder 125)
      - Bangs, John Kendrick, 1904-05 (Box 8, Folder 126)
      - Beard, Daniel C. testimonial dinner program, 1920 Feb 4 (Box 8, Folder 127)
      - Casey, Frank D., 1922, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 128)
        Related Archival Materials note
        See also: William Gallagher, Box 8, folder 140
      - Cassard, Harry L., n.d. (Box 8, Folder 129)
      - Century Company, 1892-1930 (Box 8, Folder 130)
      - Chapman, Charles exhibition ephemera, 1920, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 131)
      - Cobb, Irvin S., 1914 (Box 8, Folder 132)
      - Delineator receipt, 1913 Dec 20 (Box 8, Folder 133)
      - Diamond Toy Corporation
        - Correspondence, 1920 Jun-Aug (Box 8, Folder 134)
        - Correspondence, 1920 Sep-Dec (Box 8, Folder 135)
        - Correspondence, 1921-22 (Box 8, Folder 136)
        - Toy patents, 1921-23 (Box 8, Folder 137)
        - Toy patent assignments, 1923 (Box 8, Folder 138)
      - Frost, Arthur B., 1895-98 (Box 8, Folder 139)
      - Gallagher, William, 1920-23, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 140)
        See also: Diamond Toy Company, Box 8, folder 134
      - Harper & Brothers
        - Correspondence and advertising piece, 1887-1923, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 141)
        - Envelopes, empty, 1887-1903, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 142)
        - Royalty statements, correspondence, 1924-55 (Box 8, Folder 143)
      - Hofer, Philip, [1927?]-1956 (Box 8, Folder 144)
      - Howells, William Dean testimonial dinner ephemera, 1912 Mar (Box 8, Folder 145)
      - Jenks, Tudor, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 146)
      - Johnson, Burges, 1921 (Box 8, Folder 147)
      - Judge, 1891 (Box 8, Folder 148)
      - Library of Congress
        See: William Patten, Box 9, folder 154
      - Loomis, Charles Battell, 1901-11 (Box 8, Folder 149)
        See also: Series IX, Box 232
      - Metropolitan Museum of Art, 1926-33, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 150)
      - Navy Relief Society, 1917 (Box 8, Folder 151)
      - Paris Exposition (Exposition Universelle Internationale de 1900)
        - Guidebook, 1900 (Box 9, Folder 152)
        - Press credential, ephemera, 1900 Jun (Box 9, Folder 153)
        - Souvenir booklet, 1900
          See: Oversize, Box 241, Folder 3313
      - Patten, William, 1932-33 (Box 9, Folder 154)
      - Peck, Everett J. patent searches, 1915 (Box 9, Folder 155)
      - Periodical Publishers' Association of America: ephemera
        - First annual dinner, 1904 (Box 9, Folder 156-157)
        - Second annual dinner, 1905 (Box 9, Folder 158)
        - Third annual dinner, 1906 (Box 9, Folder 159-160)
        - [Fourth] annual dinner, 1907 (Box 9, Folder 161)
        - [Fifth] annual dinner, 1910 (Box 9, Folder 162)
        - [Sixth] annual dinner, 1911 (Box 9, Folder 163)
        - [Seventh] annual dinner, 1912 (Box 9, Folder 164)
      - Puck, 1893 (Box 9, Folder 165)
      - Reed, Myrtle, 1909, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 166)
      - Republican National Convention ephemera, 1912 Jun (Box 9, Folder 167)
      - Roosevelt Memorial Association, Inc., 1923 (Box 9, Folder 168)
      - Towne, Charles Hanson, 1918, 1922 (Box 9, Folder 169)
      - Twain, Mark invitations and ephemera, 1905-10 (Box 9, Folder 170)
      - Victor Talking Machine Company, ca. 1913 (Box 9, Folder 171)
      - Wells, Carolyn Houghton, 1901, 1920 (Box 9, Folder 172)
      - Weyhe, E., 1928-29, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 173)
      - Wheelock, Matilda Henderson, 1914 Sep 1 (Box 9, Folder 174)
      - Women's Home Companion design competition announcement, 1906 (Box 9, Folder 175)
      - The Youth's Companion statement, 1923 (Box 9, Folder 176)
      - Miscellaneous correspondents including: (Box 9, Folder 177)
        - Allen, Charles Dexter Bok, Edward Bruestle, George M. Curtiss, Philip Johnson, Merle Vogue magazine, 1893-1923, n.d.
      - Clipping files folders (empty), ca. 1910
        See: Oversize, Box 241, Folder 3314
  - PERSONAL PAPERS
    - Art Students League membership booklet, 1894-95 (Box 10, Folder 178)
    - Ashcraft family miscellaneous poems, letter, broadsides and writings, 1840-79, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 179)
    - Autograph album, Peter Newell, 1879-82 (Box 10, Folder 180)
    - Autograph album, Leona Ashcraft, 1881-84
    - Autographed cards and paper scraps, 1924-25, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 181)
    - Automobile registration card, 1914 (Box 10, Folder 182)
    - Bushnell [IL] ephemera, 1881-96 (Box 10, Folder 183)
    - Bushnell [IL] schools
      - Certificate of promotion, graduation invitation, 1878, 1880 (Box 10, Folder 184)
      - High school diploma, 1880
        See: Oversize, Box 240, Folder 3305
    - Calling cards
      - Peter and Leona Newell, with engraved copper plate, 1880s, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 185)
      - Family members, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 186)
      - Friends (Box 10, Folder 187)
    - Christmas card list, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 188)
    - Deaths
      - Newell, Peter re: illness, death and estate, 1923-24 (Box 10, Folder 189)
        See also: Series V, Box 206, Folder 2650 and Box 207, Folder 2674
      - Newell, Peter obituaries and tributes, 1924-25 (Box 10, Folder 190)
      - Newell, Peter Leonia Men's Club resolution, 1924 (Box 10, Folder 191)
      - Newell, Peter condolence letters, 1924 (Box 10, Folder 192)
      - Newell, Leona funeral and expenses, 1954 (Box 10, Folder 193)
      - Newell, Leona obituaries, 1954 (Box 10, Folder 194)
      - Newell, Leona condolence letters, 1954 (Box 10, Folder 195)
      - Newell, Leona will, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 196)
    - Exhibition admission tickets, 1884, 1901 (Box 10, Folder 197)
    - Financial records
      - Address and account [1900-03] book, 1900-12 (Box 10, Folder 198)
      - Address and account book, 1913-14
      - Bank book, Leona Newell, 1919-20 (Box 10, Folder 199)
      - Bank book, Peter Newell, 1910-19
      - Bank checks cancelled and uncancelled, 1913-22 (Box 10, Folder 200)
      - Compensation papers and forms U.S. Treasury Department and U.S. Veterans Administration, 1918-39 (Box 10, Folder 201)
      - Income tax 1919 return work sheet, 1920 (Box 10, Folder 202)
      - Insurance, disability, 1906, 1909 (Box 10, Folder 203)
      - Insurance, life, 1923-24
      - Medical receipts and prescriptions, 1926-50 (Box 10, Folder 204)
      - Price lists for art supplies, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 205)
      - Receipts, 1881, 1935 (Box 10, Folder 206)
    - Leonia [NJ] social groups and events
      - American Legion, Clendenon Newell Post, clippings and programs, 1919-20, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 207)
      - Fortnighters of Leonia programs, 1909, 1916 (Box 11, Folder 208)
      - Leonia Field Club invitations, 1895-98 (Box 11, Folder 209)
      - Leonia Lyceum programs, 1894-1908 (Box 11, Folder 210)
      - Leonia News, vol. 1, no. 4, 1903 Jun (Box 11, Folder 211)
      - Men's Neighborhood Club of Leonia miscellaneous ephemera, 1916-23 (Box 11, Folder 212)
      - Men's Neighborhood Club of Leonia Washington Commemorative Tablet unveiling ceremony, 1916 Jul 4 (Box 11, Folder 213)
      - Miscellaneous programs, tickets, invitations and handbills, ca. 1900-23 (Box 11, Folder 214)
    - MacLean, Katharine Allison poem: "To Peter Newell" typescript, 1922 Nov 26 (Box 11, Folder 215)
    - Manhattan Building (96 Fifth Avenue) artists' reception announcement, 1891 Nov 21 (Box 11, Folder 216)
    - Marriages
      - Baker, Helen Newell, divorce from Alfred Z. Baker newspaper clippings, ca. 1915[?] (Box 11, Folder 217)
      - Cosgrove, Warner G., marriage to Betty (Helen) Baker announcement and newspaper clippings, 1945 Mar (Box 11, Folder 218)
      - Gordon, Marcus, marriage to Helen Newell Baker announcement and newspaper clippings, 1924 Mar (Box 11, Folder 219)
      - McCormick, Howard, marriage to Josephine Newell announcement and newspaper clippings, 1911 May (Box 11, Folder 220)
      - Newell, Peter, marriage to Leona D. Ashcraft photocopy of newspaper clipping, [1885 Mar 7] (Box 11, Folder 221)
        See also: Oversize, Box 241, Folder 3321
      - Scott, Gherald D., marriage to Nancy McCormick invitation, 1953 Jun 13 (Box 11, Folder 222)
    - Nankivel, John Frederick tearsheets of magazine illustrations, 1903-04, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 223)
    - Palm prints of Peter Newell's hands with readings by Nellie Simmons Meier, 1910 Mar 14 (Box 11, Folder 224)
      See also: Series VII, Box 210, Folder 2771
    - Notes, notebooks and diaries
      - Address book, with notes on foreign languages and diary entry for 1917 [in unidentified hand], ca. 1903-30 (Box 11, Folder 225)
      - Address book, ca. 1950
      - Diaries [2v], Peter Newell, 1878 May-Jul (Box 11, Folder 226)
        See also: Series VIII, Box 215, Folder 2925
      - Notebook, containing [in George F. Newell's hand] genealogy notes and notes on sculpture and painting; and [in Peter Newell's hand] travel notes of trip to New York State, Baltimore and Washington, DC (1886-87), methods of caricature and a few small pencil sketches, 1882-87, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 227)
      - Newell, George Frederick genealogical notes and children's drawings on two account book pages, ca. 1856-70 (Box 11, Folder 228)
      - Miscellaneous notes and lists, 1891-1918, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 229)
      - Telephone numbers list for Leonia, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 230)
    - Real estate
      - Colorado, Colorado City deeds, 1888 (Box 11, Folder 231)
      - Nebraska, Bloomington deeds and tax receipts, 1887 (Box 11, Folder 232)
      - New Jersey, Leonia assessments and receipts, 1902 (Box 11, Folder 233)
      - New Jersey, Leonia builder's contract and receipts, 1894, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 234)
      - New Jersey, Leonia mortgage papers, satisfaction pieces and Terry account, 1894-1913 (Box 11, Folder 235)
      - New Jersey, Leonia specifications for house; H. Toler Booraem, architect, 1894 (Box 11, Folder 236)
      - New Jersey, Leonia tax bills, 1915-20 (Box 11, Folder 237)
      - New York, Little Neck bond, maps, letter and receipt, 1923-24 (Box 11, Folder 238)
    - Recipes, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 239)
    - Scrapbook kept by Peter Newell, containing clippings of work by other artists including Pyle, Renouard, Sterner, Smedley, and Wilder, ca. 1885 (Box 12, Folder 240)
    - Salmagundi Club, 1909, 1921 (Box 12, Folder 241)
    - Society of American Fakirs ephemera, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 242)
    - Stedman, Marshall poems, card and theater programs, 1898-99, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 243)
    - Stocks and certificates
      - Adams Exploration Company, 1912 (Box 12, Folder 244)